<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pis on Ed&#39;s Space - Notes</title>
    <link>/worknotes/docs/pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pis on Ed&#39;s Space - Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/worknotes/docs/pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Jetson Nano OS for Server</title>
      <link>/worknotes/docs/pi/trim-jetsonnano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/worknotes/docs/pi/trim-jetsonnano/</guid>
      <description>Reducing Jetson Nano OS for Server # The Nvidia Jetson Nano is a Single Board Computer (SBC) with a scaled-down Nvidia GPU (Tegra X1). I have the 2GB version, the smallest available. The OS that Nvidia forces you to use comes with a full-blown desktop environment, which chews through the 2GB of RAM pretty easily - not leaving as much room as I&amp;rsquo;d like for other things.
Consequently, this page is to document the steps to trim down the OS to save disk space and RAM - adding to steps documented elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Public Webserver on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>/worknotes/docs/pi/webserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/worknotes/docs/pi/webserver/</guid>
      <description>Setting Up Public Webserver on Raspberry Pi # The instructions here assumes you&amp;rsquo;re using Raspberry Pi Lite as the OS on the Raspberry Pi. Other OS&amp;rsquo; are largely similar though. The main difference will be the packages and package managers, and the firewall tool.
Setup the pi to host the server
Flash disk with raspberry pi lite. Insert disk into pi and power them on. (follow the instructions here up to step 4) Setup router to forward http/https/ssh requests to the Raspberry Pi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Raspberry Pi Slurm Cluster</title>
      <link>/worknotes/docs/pi/slurm-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/worknotes/docs/pi/slurm-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Setting Up Raspberry Pi Slurm Cluster # Flash disk(s) with raspberry pi lite. Insert disk(s) into pi(s) and power them on.
Run sudo raspi-config
update raspi-config change hostname setup ssh change password for pi user set wlan locale set timezone setup login-less ssh between nodes.
create key on one of the nodes
sudo ssh-keygen # save it somewhere central like in /etc/ssh configure ssh to use the newly created key by editing /etc/ssh/ssh_config and adding</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
