<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CUDA Programming on GraSPH Docs</title>
    <link>/docs/docs/cuda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CUDA Programming on GraSPH Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/docs/docs/cuda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CUDA &#43; NVHPC on WSL</title>
      <link>/docs/docs/cuda/cuda-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/docs/cuda/cuda-wsl/</guid>
      <description>Installing CUDA + NVHPC on WSL # This page describes the steps to setup CUDA and NVHPC within the WSL2 container (Windows 10) - avoiding the need for dual-boot or a separate Linux PC. Note that WSL2 must not have been installed when beginning these steps.
Install the latest Windows CUDA graphics driver Install WSL2 open PowerShell as administrator Make sure to update WSL kernel to latest version wsl &amp;ndash;update if accidentally rolled back, follow the instructions here then wsl &amp;ndash;update again check which Linux flavours are available with wsl &amp;ndash;list &amp;ndash;online install the desired flavour by wsl &amp;ndash;install -d start WSL with wsl, or opening the WSL application from the Windows search bar sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade -y Close and restart WSL sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt upgrade -y &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt autoremove -y Install CUDA for WSL check which CUDA version is compatible with the desired version NVHPC kit here select the correct CUDA version here Select the right setup: Linux -&amp;gt; x86_64 -&amp;gt; WSL-Ubuntu -&amp;gt; 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/docs/cuda/hidden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/docs/cuda/hidden/</guid>
      <description>This page is hidden in menu # Quondam non pater est dignior ille Eurotas # Latent te facies # Lorem markdownum arma ignoscas vocavit quoque ille texit mandata mentis ultimus, frementes, qui in vel. Hippotades Peleus pennas conscia cuiquam Caeneus quas.
Pater demittere evincitque reddunt Maxime adhuc pressit huc Danaas quid freta Soror ego Luctus linguam saxa ultroque prior Tatiumque inquit Saepe liquitur subita superata dederat Anius sudor Cum honorum Latona # O fallor in sustinui iussorum equidem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
